hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast I'm
excited to help you if you're a coach
Mentor trainer on how to grow your
business and make more money one of the
number one strategies that I've had over
the last couple of years for growing my
business is making sure to prioritize
play and particularly guilt-free
play and I think one of the problems
that people have is that when they're
building a business growing a coaching
business they believe they don't have
enough time to do things that are fun in
their life they believe that well I will
have fun when I get my to-do list done
and I can tell you this that that's
actually one of the worst things that
you can do one of the best things that
you can do is actually make time in your
schedule for guilt-free play even when
you feel like you don't have enough time
to do it and right away even what I've
just said it goes against many ingrained
beliefs that we have in our minds what
we've been told by Guru gurus and
mentors what people tell us to do and it
actually just inherently to most people
especially in business feels
wrong and yet in my experience and when
I talk to millionaires when I talk to
people that are the most successful they
say that this is this is actually one of
the most true things you I can tell you
this for me and that's really the only
thing I can draw from is my own
experience is that I am way more
creative when I take time just to have
fun when I take time to do what I want
to do when I take time to set aside the
to-do list and unplug distract and do
something else that is fun for me you
know a lot of people they just they feel
like well no if I just grind through and
I do all the stuff that I have to do
that's going to get it accomplished
that's what's going to help me do the
stuff that I have to do well that's the
furthest thing from the
truth there's nothing that I can can say
right now that's going to convince you
of that though and that's the
interesting part about this as I've been
saying this for a long time and it's one
of those areas a lot of people skip over
a lot of people ignore that a lot of
people think oh no if I can just grip
tightly and control things I can make
them happen for
me you can White Knuckle it for a while
but what is the hard work even for if
you don't give yourself time to have fun
and time to play so here's one of the
things that I would challenge you to do
is I would challenge you to explore
where does that belief come
from I can't play I Can't Have fun until
I get all my work done until I do
everything on my to-do list CU what's
going to happen is that will then become
your personality and then weeks and then
months will go by and you've been nearly
grinding and I can tell you you will be
less productive
overall when it comes to the coaching
business when it comes to the mentoring
business when it when it comes to
helping other
people when it comes to sales when it
comes to you producing the results that
you want to produce in your business
giving
yourself
opportunities to Goof Off mess around go
on a go on a on an adventure on a date
to do something that is not
productive is actually one of the most
productive things that you can do so I
would I would challenge you whether it
feels right or
not trust me on this that by you
detaching and what you want to do is
when you're doing that you want to not
process and think about all the stuff
that you have to do while you're doing
that see I I I meet some people they're
like well yeah I I take time for myself
and selfcare and I do I take a bath and
a glass of wine or I spend time with my
family but while they're doing doing
that they're thinking about all the
stuff they have to do in their business
they're thinking about all the stuff
that they're not doing and that's where
the guilt comes in or they're saying
well I'm just multitasking I'm being
productive by multitasking multiple
ideas it's a
lie it's a
facade so I want to challenge you what
if and maybe you can't turn it off and
that's one of those things for you to
maybe grow into is learning how to be
present while you're having fun learning
how to be present and still while you're
doing those things I can tell you you're
going to come up with a thousand one
reasons why you
can't what are you trying to avoid and
that's where see this is the fun part
about
it when you do the stuff that's actually
fun and enjoyable for you and the
thoughts come into your
head that's actually what's really
bothering in you beneath the surface you
know for me when I play when I have fun
I have things that come up my to-do list
ideas like that you know interestingly
enough for me it's actually enjoyable
for me to
um do the
dishes which is funny I I enjoy doing
the dishes and
yet I come up with all these things I
need to do when I'm doing the
dishes
and then I start making notes as to what
those are and stuff like that and
creativity starts coming through my
brain so when you detach from the doing
all the time of the obligations of what
you feel like I must do and I must grind
and I must go into and that frustration
and that trying to make it
happen when you can detach from
that temporarily that need to have a
tight grip and control everything to
make it happen for you and you can let
go and you can say you know what I'm
going to let go and it's okay if I miss
a day of productivity to do XYZ you want
to know what's going to happen it will
rewire certain parts of your brain when
you can truly do this when you can truly
tap into not doing all these things and
it's scientifically
proven that having more fun in your life
is productive in fact you know I was
thinking about doing this we're going to
go live right now and I'm actually going
to log
into a really fun site that we've been
using with
AI and we're actually going to find what
is the scientific evidence of this and
I'm going to ask it what is the
scientific evidence that play in
guilt-free play is actually more
productive for people in
business and perplexity is going to go
to work and it's going to actually pull
this up some of these benefits that an
actual surprising way to boost your
productivity is play that even in high
pressure
environments that whether it be playing
a video game or just doing something
that's out of the norm of what you need
to do produces productivity scientific
evidence suggests that play and
guilt-free play can increase
productivity
uh it's
essential for achieving quality work and
minimizing procrastination that's the
crazy part it minimizes
procrastination it enhances creativity
and creates more of
those aha
moments the distance from haha to Aha is
short and often fun leads to
unexpected
Innovation improved well-being your
you're going to be happier your mental
health is going to be
there what are some examples that play
can increase productivity in our lives
and this is this is just looking up
articles and stuff on this right
here there are examples like team
building office games things like that
camaraderie uh okay so like obviously
like those are some different examples
but what I want to tell you is this okay
that the
belief
that I need to quote unquote do
everything
perfectly and not
play the fear the fear of missing out by
doing fun things and needing to grind
and nose to the grindstone mindset
how can you break this and give yourself
a chance to play you know if I ask the
AI that the whole the fear of missing
out of opportunities and things like
that Breaking Free from this mindset
allows you to shift into that behavior
recognizing that you actually need to
maybe set some
boundaries to where you set boundaries
so you don't feel guilty and you allow
yourself to play you accept the
trade-off of maybe I'm not going to
accomplish something and so much beauty
comes out of this and so I would just
encourage you if you're listening to
this right now if you're watching this
start to do some more fun things how do
you come up with some of those ideas and
what those fun things are what did you
do when you were a
child what did you do when you were a
kid that you goofed off and
did what are the things that you wish
that you could do when you got all your
stuff done
what are some things that you tell
yourself oh I can't do this until I get
my whole to-do list
done you know I've seen some people they
make a joke out of it and they're like
oh well I like to you know and then they
give like this business thing that they
like to do or I do business for fun I
did that I told myself that for years I
was in
denial of the
fact that I was I was actually operating
out of trauma by guide by by grinding
trying to do all the stuff that I felt
that I had to do and not giving myself
opportunities to
play and really it could just be a
trauma response that's at that's at work
here that's causing you to feel like oh
I can't do that and so I so think about
what are some of those things that maybe
you even got in trouble for when you
were younger or you feel guilty doing
those guilty pleasures that's one of the
thing those guilty pleasures and then
instead of doing it and then feeling
guilt afterwards doing it and not
feeling the guilt
afterwards there's there's a release
that
happens there's a there's a powerful
positive benefit from giving yourself
the opportunity to watch a TV
show waste
time
you know I see a lot of people they have
religious reasons they literally feel
like they can't because religion has
them convinced that it is disobedient to
God to waste time I've seen this happen
with some
people and they won't allow themselves
to have fun and and and yet they're
[Applause]
literally they're literally not being
productive there re many of the times I
see the reasons why people won't let's
go let's go after like the religious
one well I need to be productive and
every minute needs to produce what God
has called me to do well guess what did
you know that you're actually missing
out on many of the things that you are
called to produce by not being willing
to quote unquote waste time and you're
actually operating out of a scarcity
mindset instead of an abundance
mindset okay and so when you can get
this when you can really Digest what I'm
sharing right
now it will
unlock massive levels
of creativity
productivity Clarity on things you're
stuck
on
happiness you know if you find yourself
in anxiety and stress and things like
that trying to make things happen in
your life trying to work so hard to make
them come together gosh I just need to
make this thing come
together maybe you're somebody you're
like everything comes easy to me in all
other areas of my life except this one
thing that I'm trying to make
happen that actually the
key is to step back to give yourself a
break to have some fun to not strive so
hard and then come back later with A New
Perspective
it's such a huge strategy for Success
that is so missed and it's even
condemned and yet and it's condemned by
very successful people too but they
always end up hitting a plateau where
they want to go to the next level of
success and they say gosh I wish I knew
this
sooner and I'm giving it to you right
now I'm giving you a framework that will
literally transform your life if you
listen to it many will not but it will
change your life for the better listen
if this podcast episode has helped you
share it with somebody don't hold this
to yourself make changes in your life to
grow your life and reach your goals talk
soon everybody have a good
[Music]
[Applause]
one